Documents the history of gays and lesbians in Hollywood films.
Fabulous! The Story of Queer Cinema is a documentary
film directed by Lesli Klainberg.
A chronological look at films by, for, or about gays and lesbians in the United States,
from 1947 to 2005, Kenneth Anger's "Fireworks" to "Brokeback Mountain".
Talking heads, anchored by critic and scholar B.
Ruby Rich, are interspersed with an advancing timeline
and with clips from two dozen films.
The narrative groups the pictures around various firsts, movements, and triumphs: experimental films, indie films, sex on screen, outlaw culture and bad guys, lesbian lovers, films
about AIDS and dying, emergence of romantic comedy, transgender films, films about diversity and various cultures, documentaries and then mainstream Hollywood drama.
What might come next?
Self, played by B. Ruby Rich.
Self, played by John Waters.
Self, played by Jane Lynch.
Self, played by Alan Cumming.
Self, played by Heather Matarazzo.
Self, played by Todd Haynes.
This article lists lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, or queer-related films
involving representation of fictional and factual LGBTQ people.
The list includes films that feature an LGBTQ story,
or deal with significant LGBTQ issues.
These films may involve participation by LGBTQ cast, producer,
director, or crew; or a focus on LGBTQ target audiences.
The English film title, original title, country of
origin and production year are listed.
Order is alphabetical by title.
There are also lists of LGBTQ films by year, by
storyline, by characters, and directed by women.
The film explores themes of lgbt, woman director, gay theme.